Todd Drinkwater

Full-Stack Web Developer

0	github.com/todddrinkwater
in	www.linkedin.com/in/todd-drinkwater
C	027 421 9065
$\mathbf{\sim}$	todddrinkwaternz@gmail.com

About Me

I am a developer with a background in education. Combining my passion for technology and love of learning, I quickly make use of new programming concepts to turn them into a reality. My experience as a teacher has made me an effective problem solver, negotiator and communicator. Since undertaking a journey into web development, I have completed over 2000 hours in learning technical and non-technical development skills (including team, pairing and individual projects) and have become enthusiastic about writing eloquent code to provide creative solutions to real world problems. I am now looking for my first role as a web developer.

Skills

Technical Experience

Languages	Key Frameworks & Libraries	Tools	Approaches
HTML 5	React	Git	Agile
CSS 3	Redux	GitHub	Test Driven
JavaScript ES2015	Webpack	Unit Testing	Development
Python 3	Express	Waffle	
	KnexJS	Trello	
	SQLite3	Slack	

Soft-Skills

Communication & Empathy

- Seven years working as a teacher in multiple disciplines, with differing age groups, gender, cultural identities, and learning abilities. Positions were located both in New Zealand and the United Kingdom.
- I can negotiate with a range of people in both a technical and non-technical environment.

A Safe Pair of Hands

• I have taught and led high-risk activities such as rock climbing, snowboarding, and hiking with up to 100 students at a time.

• Spent four years as Teacher-in-Charge of the Fraser High School Junior Outdoor Education Programme. This involved organising outdoor experiences for students, promoting trips at school assemblies, completing risk assessments and communicating with parents and the senior leadership team.

Independent learner

• While originally not trained as a Science teacher, I spent a year teaching myself and my students Science in the UK. Specialising in Senior Physics, my GCSE (NCEA equivalent) students gained a 91% pass rate with 75% gaining a A – A* grade.

Experience

Enspiral Dev Academy (Wellington, NZ)

2016 - 2017 (Nov - May)

EDA was an intensive 5-month course that allowed me to gain a fully immersive experience into web development. Described as an "apprenticeship on steroids", I quickly advanced from using basic HTML to being able to develop a web application, full-stack. A typical day at EDA consisted of morning and afternoon lectures, followed by pair programming challenges. Fridays allowed for personal or group project challenges which provided the opportunity to work effectively as a team and develop multiple features simultaneously using GitHub.

The final bootcamp phase of the course challenged me to better develop my skills as a junior developer by taking a more independent approach to problem-solving. Problems were often solved by talking through code to myself, pseudocode, searching through websites such as Stack Overflow and reaching out to other cohort members. During this time, I also took part in Engineering Empathy workshops to continue to enhance my awareness of self and other. Final projects allowed us 8 days to create a fully working application that was to be deployed to Heroku. Taking a large amount of time to thoroughly conduct our planning meant our week flowed smoothly with few issues. We were able to successfully develop an MVP for our product, focusing on getting communities to share and make better use of their personal resources. Since graduating I have continued to work on further projects as seen on my GitHub portfolio.

See skills section for a full-range of technical skills learnt during the course.

Teacher of Physical and Outdoor Education – Fraser High School (Hamilton, NZ) 2010-2013, 2016 – 2017 (Jan – Dec)

- Motivating and engaging a diverse range of students in lessons, using initiative and problem-solving skills, and working together with staff and students to help create a safe and productive working environment where positive relationships can be formed. I taught the year levels of 9 to 12, including NCEA levels 1 and 2.
- Year 9 and 10 Health with experience also in teaching FRIENDS Health programme initiatives.
- Teacher-in-charge of Senior Council and Ball Committee.
- Rock Climbing Instructor for the school climbing club.
- Teacher-in-Charge of Junior Outdoor Education Programme (bushcraft, rafting skills, water safety, skiing and snow Boarding)

- Led professional development in SOLO Taxonomy, Junior Curriculum Development and cultural games for the Physical Education department.
- Teaching students with physical and intellectual disabilities.

Teacher of Science - Fulham College Boys' School (London, UK)

2015 (Jan - Dec)

- 91% pass rate of my students (including 75% A*-A grade) in GCSE Physics.
- Working in a multi-cultural state school that has achieved 'outstanding' in student progress.
- Key Stages 3 & 4 (including GCSE Physics and Biology).
- Teaching science theory and practical knowledge, running tutorials and participating in ongoing professional development.
- Required excellent classroom management strategies due working in an environment with challenging behaviour.

Supply (Relief) Teacher – Vibe Teacher Recruitment (London, UK)

2014 (Jan - Dec)

- Providing relief cover for various schools around London.
- Schools varied in ethos, private and public status, behavioural issues and achievement.
- Teacher cover would often vary between a day and up to 6 weeks at a time.

Education

2006 – 2009 Bachelor of Teaching
 University of Waikato, New Zealand

 2006 – 2009 Bachelor of Sport and Leisure Studies
 University of Waikato, New Zealand

Interests

Guitar • Photography • Snow Boarding • Coding • Reading • Fitness • Travel • TaeKwon-Do

References

Available on request.